External validation indices are
外部评价指标
the scoring methods we use when we have a labeled datasets,
是当我们的数据集有标签时
and we run a clustering on it.
使用的评分方法
This is a subset of the scoring methods that we have available.
这是我们可用的评分方法的一个子集
This is not all of them,
这些指标并不是所有外部评价指标
this is just some of them, there are a lot more.
这些只是其中一些
Some of them are available in Scikit-learn as we'll see.
我们将会看到其中的一些用于 Scikit-learn
And, each of these,
对于每一个指标
we give them the original labels and the labels resulting from the clustering,
我们给予它源自聚类的原始标签
and they give us a score in this range.
它们就会产生一个在这个范围区间的得分
So, it's mostly in zero to one,
大多都在 0 到 1 这个区间
while Adjusted Rand Score gives us a range between minus one and one.
但调整兰德系数的得分区间为 -1 到 1
Let's look at how Adjusted Rand Index is calculated.
我们来看看调整兰德系数的计算
So, let's say we have this labeled datasets,
假如这是我们有标签的数据集
and these are the actual labels.
这些标签都是真实标签
Let's say we run K-means or any other clustering methods on it,
我们对其使用 K 均值或其它聚类方法
and we get this clustering.
然后得到这个聚类
So, it's not exactly the same as the actual label.
所以 这和实际的标签不完全一样
So, let's first calculate the Rand Index,
首先我们计算 Rand Index
and then calculate the Adjusted Rand Index.
然后再计算 调整兰德系数
The formula for calculating the Rand Index is a plus b,
计算 Rand Index 的算式是 a+b
over n, choose two.
除以 n x 2
a is the number of pairs that were in the same cluster
a 表示在聚类 C
in C and remain to be in the same cluster in K,
与聚类 K 中
the same cluster as each other,
都是同类元素的对数
regardless of the label of that cluster.
不考虑那个聚类的标签
And so, let's count it here.
我们计算其对数
So, we have these two,
有两对
or we have this pair that was in the same cluster in C,
或者说 聚类 K 中的这对元素
and remains to be in the same cluster as each other in K. So that's one.
与聚类 C 中的这对元素一样 所以这是一对
And then, we have this pair.
接着
It was in the same cluster in C and remains to be in the same cluster in K,
聚类 C 中的这对元素在聚类 K 中也保持一样
and then so that is two.
所以有两对
Every pair including this point is discounted because it's switched.
每对包含这个点的对不算 因为这个点变了
So, we end up with a equal to 2. b is the number of pairs that were in
所以 a=2
different clusters in C and remain in different clusters in K. And so, let's count them.
b 表示在聚类 C 与聚类 K 中都是不同类别的元素对数
So, this pair was in different clusters in C,
所以 这对元素在聚类 C 中不是同类元素
and remains to be in different clusters in K. So, that's one.
在聚类 K 中也不是同类元素 所以这是一对
And then, we have this pair, these two points here.
然后这对 这两个点
They were different in C, and they were different in K. So that's two.
在聚类 C 中不是同类元素 在聚类 K 中也不是同类元素 两对
And then, these two as number three,
然后 这两个点是第三对
and these two, that is pair number four. And, that's it.
还有这两个点 第四对 一共有四对
None of the pairs involving the central point can count.
不含中心点的对可以计数
So, b is equal to four.
所以 b=4
And n is basically the number of samples or points that we have.
而 n 基本上就是我们拥有的样本数量或点数
So that is just five.
所以 n=5
And so, that actually turns out to be just six over ten.
所以结果是十分之六
That is the Rand Index.
这就是 Rand Index
To calculate the Adjusted Rand Index,
要计算 调整兰德系数
we just discount the expected index.
我们只需代入这个公式
There's a little bit more details about this calculation in the text below the video.
在视频下面的文字中有关于此计算的更多细节
Let's use Adjusted Rand Index to compare to K-means clusterings.
我们将 调整兰德系数 与 K 均值聚类进行比较
Let's say we have this dataset,
假如我们有这个数据集
and these are the original labels.
这些是初始标签
We call them the ground truth.
我们称之为真相
So, this is a labeled dataset that we have,
这是我们有标签的数据集
and we run K-means one time,
我们对其进行 K 均值聚类
and we get this result.
结果就是这样
So, it's not perfectly matching the ground truth.
它与真相并不是完美匹配
So, these three points are purple here,
这三个点在这里是紫色的
but they are orange here.
但在这里却是橘黄色
So, it's not 100%,
所以并不是 100% 匹配
it didn't get the actual labels 100% like the ground truth.
它没有使真实标签与真相 100%相似
But how much or how well did it do?
但它做到了多少呢
If we calculate the Adjusted Rand Index,
如果我们计算 调整兰德系数
it will be 0.84.
结果是 0.84
Is that good? Is that bad?
这样的结果是好还是不好呢
I mean we can use that to compare.
我们可以进行比较
So, let's say we have another K-means clustering.
假如我们有另一个 K 均值聚类
But, let's say this one uses a different, maybe, initialization parameters,
但是 这个使用了不同的初始化参数
it runs for a different number of iterations,
进行了不同次数的迭代
and you can clearly see that it's different in a few ways.
你可以清楚地看到它们在几个方面有所不同
It's hard to tell just by looking which one is better.
只通过看很难判定那个更好
Better here means matching to the ground truth or the original labels of the dataset,
或与真相或数据集的原始标签更加匹配
but we can just simply calculate the Adjusted Rand Index,
但我们可以计算 调整兰德系数
and that would turn out to be 0.86.
结果为 0.86
And so, this has a higher score than this, and so,
这个比这个的得分高 所以
this K-means clustering is better than this,
这个 K 均值聚类更好
or matches the ground truth better than this one does.
或者说更与真相匹配
And we can contrast that with a Random Assignment,
我们可以将其与随机分配的进行比较
where we have randomly or arbitrarily picked cluster for each of the points,
我们为每个点随机或任意选择一个聚类
and the Adjusted Rand Index here would be very close to zero.
其 调整兰德系数 值将接近 0